# **Akinola David Ayoola**

## Web Developer

David is a goal-oriented solution seeker, with a strong commitment to collaborative and innovative problem-solving. He makes use of various web development technologies like Javascript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS (SASS), NodeJs etc. to create customer-focused web applications. He is committed to high standards in user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users and successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective project delivery and customer

# Work History

## 2019-02 - Software/DHIS2 Developer

EHealth4eeryone, Garki, Abuja, FCT

- Developed the MPD4QED project software, mobile application and dedicated browser for WHO within 5 months. This is in use across 60+ locations in Nigeria.
- Conducted project capacity training for 200+ attendees across 4 locations, Also Conducted advanced training in the DHIS2 software for 20+ individuals across 3 locations.
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple projects.
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in software development projects. Resulting in a 10% reduction of time spent in development on average.
- Introduced methodologies and best practices to software development division to enhance product definition and application customization.
- Resolved technical problems, improved operations and provided exceptional client support across company projects.

## 2016-08 - Freelance Lead Developer

## Current

Deanav Ventures - Hidden Hyve, Abuja, FCT

- Developed websites (eCommerce, portfolios, business) with functional dashboards and custom pages on contract. This resulted in a 30% average increase in business sales and a high level of customer satisfaction.
- Supervised the completion of major projects. following appropriate SDLC methods.
- Created Mock-ups and prototypes for projects using modern tools such as AdobeXD, Justinmind prototyper, Figma Design, Photoshop etc.
- Designed and Deployed a twitter-notification bot that provides information about available Nigerian Jobs. This has provided Nigerians access to job opportunities online
- Mentored junior and intermediate developers.

#### 2020-03 -2020-05

#### React Developer (Remote)

Friyay.io, Greenville, USA

- Created a chrome extension application based on React, integrating Facebook's best practices for interface design.
- · Integrated new interfaces with backend systems using microservices.
- Implemented three major new enhancements to existing application designs.
- Built, tested and deployed a scalable, highly available and modular application.

# 2017-01 - IT Associate (Intern)

# 2017-07

National Info & Tech Development Agency, Garki, Abuja, FCT

- Developed an intranet website that reduced the need for physical communication and file transfer by roughly 30%.
- · Re-designed the office's internet website that improved user experience by 80%.

# **Education**

# 2014-09 - Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

#### 2018-06 Landmark University - Omu-aran Kwara

Graduated in Top 10% of Class.

- Recipient of the NNPC national merit scholarship
- Executive member of the Computer Science Student Association (NACOSS).

# Q Contact

### Address

Abuja, FCT, 900211

#### Phone

+2349015480795

## E-mail

ayooladavid@gmail.com

## www

https://dqve.github.io

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.co m/in/david-avo/



### Javascript (ES2019)

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SASS

## React, React Native

Webnack, Babel, Eslint. Gulp, NuxtJs, GatsBy, Git

AdobeXD, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Illustrator, Figma Design, Sketch

MySql

Php

Python, NLP, Deep Learning

Redux, MobX

Wordnress

NodeJs, Laravel, Flask



- Excellent collaboration and organisation
- Algorithmic implementation of software solutions
- Keen and proactive problem solving
- Innovation and creativity
- · Passionate about technology and creating technological solutions
- Fast learner
- Good public speaking, tutoring and communication skills
- Understanding and improvements of UI and Usability



- Elected to the following positions for NACOSS: General Secretary in 2016, Interim President in 2017, Financial Secretary in 2017.
  - Awarded Runner-up most entrepreneurial student 2018, Runner-up most innovative student 2018.
    - Appointed Co-unit lead of TOP in 2017.
    - Awarded Most innovative unit member, TOP in 2018. Founded and led the student tech initiative "Smart
    - trybe", in 2017

# Recent Projects

https://qbingo.netlify.app/for-e4e/

Type: Web Application Back-end tools: Google spreadsheet API

Front-end tools: JavaScript, SaaS Description:

This is a web application game that allows a user to generate dynamic bingo boards, select bingo cards and download their final boards. It also contains a scoring mechanism and a dedicated leader board.

#### LinkedIn (clone)

https://linkedin-react.netlifv.app/

Type: Web Application

Back-end tools: Docker, redux-thunk Front-end tools: JavaScript, Redux, SAAS, reactJs, redux

Description:

This is a web application that provides LinkedIn like services, and simple management of users, companies, iobs etc.

It provides a robust system for employee management free of charge.

### Mimo

https://github.com/dgve/mimo

Type: Web Application

Back-end tools: Firebase, Hasura Front-end tools: JavaScript, ContextAPI, React

Description: This is a browser extension that extends the usability of

the homepage of your browser. It displays information tailored to your specific (religious/non-religious) preferences, e.g Time and date, weather information, quotes, bible verses/Quran quotes note-book, tasktracker etc. It allows users to unload external

applications unto the homepage also. DTX

https://dqve.github.io/dix/source

Type: Web Application Back-end tools: WebAudioAPI

Front-end tools: JavaScript, HTML, CSS Description:

This is a decibel meter calculator built using the web audio API. It calculates the decibel count of sound in the

environment and displays a warning if a previously set threshold is passed.

## Freebee

https://dqve.github.io/30-Days-30-Projects Type: Variable

Back-end tools: None

Front-end tools: JavaScript, HTML, CSS etc

Description:

This is a collation of free website templates, webpages and software I have made over time.

#### LINKS TO OTHERS: https://scpc.lmu.edu.na

http://kallwealth.com

https://denamgroup.com

etc.

# Referees

- · Mr Asani Oluwatobi, Lecturer, Landmark University. 0803 577 6226
- Mrs Antonia Odiokwu, Supervisor, NITDA, ugomtonia@gmail.com
- Blessing Philips, HOD, eHealth4everyone. bphilips.e4e@gmail.com

• EC Council - Certified Secured Computer User

2016-02 Sololearn - Certificate

2017-05

in the following languages : Javascript, PHP, HTML, CSS, JAVA, C++, SQL

 CISCO - Certificate of completion of IT

Essentials course 2018-06 CISCO - Certificate of

participation in introduction to Computer Networking

# **M** Honors and Awards

#### AWARDS:

Award received in recognition of stellar performance as the employee of the

June, July & November 2019 at ehealth4evervone. Award received in

recognition of stellar

months of April,

employee of the second and third quarter of 2019 at ehealth4everyone. Pluralsight 92%

Expert in JavaScript NNPC national merit scholarship award from NNPC

 Exemplary Student Award in Innovation and **Creativity Category** at Landmark

University

 Award of excellence as the co-lead of the Landmark University TOP Unit head 2018

etc More info can be found on my LinkedIn page.



English

set.

Yoruba



- Internet of things Virtual and Augmented
- reality development
- · Virtual assistant development
- IOS Development in
- Open sourced collaborations and
- developments Computer programming training and advancement of local programming

knowledge